# Amar Raj Ghimire

 ■ +977-9849850456
 Image: Legisland of the complex of the complex

### Personal Profile \_\_\_

I am a passionate physics student with a keen interest in studying black holes, gravitational waves, and the early universe. Having obtained my Bachelor's and Master's degrees in Physics from Tribhuvan University, Nepal, I have developed a solid foundation in both theoretical and experimental physics. . My research experience encompasses studying null geodesics around Schwarzschild black holes, analyzing the relative abundances of gas-rich galaxies, and investigating gravitational wave signals from binary neutron star mergers. I am also proficient in Python programming and have experience with various data science libraries. Furthermore, I am an active member of several physics organizations and have presented my research at international conferences and attended many workshops and schools related to Physics and Computer programming. Overall, I am a dedicated individual with a passion for unraveling the mysteries of the cosmos. Also, I believe,teaching high school students will be so much beneficial for me to continue my passion.

In addition, I have accomplished all the written exams in Political Science and am currently working on my thesis

### **Education**

M.A. Political Science

Kathmandu,Nepal

Kathhmandu Private college,Tribhuvan University 2019-2022 (Thesis year running)

M.Sc. in Physics

Patan Multiple Campus, Tribhuvan University, Lalitpur, Nepal (3.5 CGPA)

2017 - 2019

**B.Sc.** in Physics

Trichandra College, Tribhuvan University, Ghantaghar, Kathmandu, Nepal (56%)

2011 - 2015

### **Research and Projects**

i. Study of null geodesics around Schwarzschild Black hole

(**Univeristy Project Third sem MSc**: Advisor: Assistant Professor Mr. Yogesh Singh Maharjan, Tribhuvan University)

Feb 2020 - Apr 2020

ii. Study of Relative abundances of Gas Rich Galaxies to constrain the Early Nucleosynthesis Model

(**Master Dissertation**: Under the supervision of Dr. suraj Poudel, Pontifolic Catholic University, Valpraso, Chile and Mr. Yogesh Singh Maharjan, Assistant Prof, Tribhuvan University)

Oct 2020 - Sep 2022

iii. Study of Gravitational Wave Signals from the Binary Neutron Stars Merger using LIGO/VIRGO/KAGRA Open Data

(**Project**: With a group of Experts Dr. Sudarshan Karki,**LIGO** Project, Naresh Adhikari (PhD Scholar),Shusant Sharma (PhD Scholar))

July 2022 - ongoing

iv. Study of z  $\sim$  5 absorbing systems with high resolution data

(**Project**: Under the supervison of Dr. Suraj Poudel ,Texas Christian University,Texas,US)

Nov 2022 - ongoing

### **Involvement**.

**Member** Member, Global Hands-On Universe (GHOU)( 2020 )

**Comittee member** Patan Physics Council, Lalitpur, Nepal (2019-)

Skills

**Python:** Scipy, astropy, Scikit-learn, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Pyinstaller, OOP, tkinter, Django

Other: FORTRAN, HTML/CSS, C, C++

**Miscellaneous:** Linux, 上TEX( Overleaf, **Beamer**), Microsoft Office, **Git**.

Completed Courses: Getting Started with Deep Learning, NVIDIA DLI, 2023 march 30, Certificate Link

**Running Courses:** Udemy- The Data Science Course 2022:Complete Data Science Bootcamp

**NVIDIA-DLI-**Accelerating End-to-End Data Science Workflows
-Disaster Risk Monitoring Using Satellite Imagery

Datacamp (Nepal) - Machine Learning Fundamentals with Python

### Scholarships and Grants \_\_\_\_\_\_

2020	Full Scholarship on Second Winter School-2019 in Artificial Intelligence, Nepal Applied
	Mathematics and Informatics Institute for Re- search (NAAMI)

- 2019 Master Thesis Support Program 2019-2020 , United Grant Comission (UGC), Nepal Government
- 2014 **Graduation Scholarship**, Trichandra college, Ghantaghar Kathmandu, Nepal

### Publications and Presentations

2022 Analysis of the Null Geodesics in Schwarzschild De-Sitter Space-Time, Link

Study of Relative Abundances of Gas-Rich Galaxies to Constrain the Early Nucleosynthesis

- 2022 **Model**, Growing Black Holes: Accretion and mergers, 15-20 May 2022, **Poster Link** and a brief oral presentation
- 2020 A refresher book on "Global Governance",
  Global Books Distributors Pvt .Ltd.,Bagbazar,Kathmandu
- 2019 A refresher book on "Research Methods In Public Adminstration", Global Books Distributors Pvt .Ltd.,Bagbazar,Kathmandu

### **Experiences**

#### As a Science Teacher:

 $3^{rd}$  Feb 2016 -  $30^{th}$  Dec 2018 Mount Everest Secondary School , Kageshwari Manahara Municipality , Thali , Kathmandu Selected Workshops and Schools:

2022	IAU Symposium 375 , The Multimessenger Chakra of Blazar Jets,December 5-9,2022,Kathmandu ,Nepal

**2022** Workshop on deep learning using Supercomputer,21st Aug 2022,Organized by KUCMC,Kathmandu University,Nepal

Joint ICTP-IAEA Advanced School/Workshop on Computational Nuclear Science and Engineering ", 23 - 27 May 2022,Organized by ICTP,Italy.

**2022** Growing Black Holes: Accretion and mergers, 15-20 May 2022

2022 Young Researchers' Workshop on Machine Learning for Materials ", 09 - 13 May 2022 Organized by ICTP, Italy click here

Third Winter School-2019 in Artificial Intelligence, 20 Dec 2021 to 30 Dec 2021, Organized by Nepal Applied Mathematics and Informatics Institute for Research (NAAMI). (As a Teaching Assistant).

2020 Kathmandu Astrophysics School-Part I, Introduction to Astrophysical Data Analysis and techniques,9th November 2020 to 1st February 2021.

2020	Radio Astronomy Workshop(RAW) on CASA Pipeline for ALMA Data 2020(RAW CASA-ALMA 2020),19th Nov 2020,Radio Cosmology Research Laboratory,University of Malaya ,Malaysia
2020	4 Days Workshop on Mathematics for Machine Learning, 19 October-22 October 2020 organized by EXCESS Nepal
2020	Online School on Space and Atmospheric Physics, August 5-7, 2020, Organized by Department of Physics, St. Xavier's College, Kathmandu in collaboration with Universidade do Vale do Paraíba, Brazil.
2020	Scientific Data Analysis and Data Workshop 2020, from June 14 to july 05 2020, Oraganized by <b>Datanox</b> .
2020	"Virtual Meeting on Compact Stars and QCD 2020",International Center for Theoretical Sciences (ICTS),from 17 Aug to 21 Aug 2020 , India
2020	Winter School on Astronomy,16 Feb 2020 to 21 Feb 2020,Birla Science Center <b>Hyderabad, India</b>
2020	Second Winter School-2019 in Artificial Intelligence,10 Dec 2019 to 20 Dec 2019 ,Organized by Nepal Applied Mathematics and Informatics Institute for Research( <b>NAAMI</b> )
2019	GHOU's First Asia Regional Conference,7th to 9th March 2019 Organized by: Global Hands ON Universe(GHOU),Mars Academy USA,Prithvi Narayan Campus (Pokhara),Pokhara Research Initiatives(PRI),Orion Space Pvt. Ltd. ,Pokhara Astronomical Society ,Research Center for Applied Science and Technology(RECAST) Nepal
2018	The Physics Without Frontiers Winter School 2018, Dec 19 to 21 2018, Organized by :ICTP, US-ATLAS and Kathmandu University
2017	Workshop On Mathmatica ,2017 ,Organized by: Physics Research Initiatives(PRI),Pokhara.
2017	Nepal-Us Workshop on Applied Sciences and Industry Academia Forum 2017 Organized by:Research Center for Applied Science and Technology ( RECAST ),Nepal

### **Participations:**

2020	One day Webinar on "Numerical Simulation using Mapple-2020,NSUM-2020",19 th september 2020 ,Binary Semantics ltd, India
2020	Webinar on "Solar Coronal Holes and Their Roles in Space Weather",26 th june 2020,Nepal Physical Society and Nepal Science and Research Society,Kathmandu.
2019	First National Continuing Professional Development (CPD) Program On "RADIOTHERAPY ONGOING IN NEPAL" 28 TH th September 2019,Organized by: Medical Physicist And Radiotherapy Technologist Team Of Nepal
2019	Global Moon Landing 50 event as part of the IAU 100 celebrations in 2019, Organized by Nepelese Space Research Association (NESRA).
2019	Second National Space Meet Of Nepal(NSM 2019) ,Organized by: Space Generation Advisory Council (SGAC)
2018	Second National Symposium of Magnetic Resonance Imaging 2018 Organized by: Medical Imaging Technology Student's Society (NAMS)
2018	First National Space Meet Nepal 2018 Organized by: Space Generation dvisory Council (SGAC), Nepal

## References\_\_\_\_\_

- Dr. Lekhnath Mishra
   Head of Physics Department, Patan Multiple Campus, Lalitpur, Nepal lmisira@gmail.com
- Dr. Suraj Poudel
   Postdoctoral Research Associate,
   Dept. of Physics and Astronomy,Texas Christian University,Texas,US suraj.poudel@tcu.edu
- Mr. Yogesh Singh Maharjan
   Assistant Professor, Amrit Science College, Kathmandu Lecturer, Patan Multiple Campus, Lalitpur, Nepal yogesh.maharjan@pmc.edu.np
- Dr. Sudarshan Karki
   Postdoctoral Scholar, Missouri University of Science and Technology
   sudarshanjkarki@gmail.com

last updated : May 13, 2023

MAY 13, 2023